Jackie Martin Papers
Jackie Martin Papers
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing, general
    - Jackie Martin to unidentified, first name only, 1965-1969 (Box 4)
- Financial records
  - Financial records and office files, 1924-1968
    - Income tax figures, 1924-1954; 14 folders (Box 5)
    - Income tax figures, 1955-1964; 10 folders (Box 6)
    - Income tax figures, 1965-1967; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Receipts, American Battle Monuments Commission, 1967-1968 (Box 7)
    - Automobile history, owned by Jackie Martin (Box 7)
    - Insurance, auto, damage, history (Box 7)
    - Insurance, life, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Insurance, camera (Box 7)
    - Insurance, general (Box 7)
    - Insurance, Civil Service Retirement (Box 7)
    - Insurance, vitrine glass, damaged in transport (Box 7)
    - Legal, lease of office in National Press Building (Box 7)
    - Record of U.S. Military Service (Box 7)
    - Record of Social Security (Box 7)
    - Record of U.S. Government Service (Box 7)
  - Norwood Studios, 1960-1963; 27 folders
    - Distribution lists, media and others (Box 7)
    - Distribution lists, mailing list for Norwood Studios (Box 7)
    - Research files
      - Non-theatrical areas of study, 1960 (Box 7)
      - U.S. Chamber of Commerce, AFL job (Box 7)
      - National Trust/National Wildlife (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, Women's Life Insurance (Box 7)
    - Newsletters
      - "Washington Report", United Auto Workers (Box 7)
      - "The Viewer", 1960-1963; Jackie Martin editorial consultant (Box 7)
    - Proposals
      - AFL-CIO, Parts I, II, III (Box 7)
      - Kennedy record album, See Memorablia: Audio and sound recordings
    - Background file: brochures (Box 7)
    - Film project: "Fifty States of the U.S." (Box 8)
    - Manuscript: "Delaware" (Box 8)
    - Transcripts Talks from the Public Relations Institute, University of Wisconsin, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Records: Production record of movies (Box 8)
    - Fact sheets, background on Norwood Studio's staff (Box 8)
    - Clippings: Publicity for Norwood Studios (Box 8)
    - Press releases: from Norwood (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
      - Re: relocation of Norwood Studios (Box 8)
    - Lists: Motion Pictures in the U.S. (Box 8)
    - Subject files
      - History of clients and special services (Box 8)
      - "Filmed Features" idea and clippings, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - Frank Dennis Golf Project (Box 8)
  - Office, 1959-1969
    - Annual Newspaper Awards (Box 8)
    - Book publishing idea, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Christmas suggestions (Box 8)
    - Creative Communications, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Fashion show idea, 1959 (Box 8)
    - "Foreign Service Day" conference, 1966 (Box 8)
    - "Heartbeat of Washington" news column proposal, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Home improvement, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Items to purchase (Box 8)
    - "Jackie in Movieland: Hollywood Stars" book proposal also publicity and background information, 1965-1969 (Box 8)
    - Notes, appointment book (Box 8)
    - The maid (Box 8)
    - "Motorcare Responsibility Policy", 1967 (Box 8)
    - National Press Building Library proposal, 1965 (Box 8)
    - New business leads, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Paris fiction story, Louis Folquet correspondence, 1965 (Box 8)
    - "Pay-Say", 1959-1966 (Box 8)
    - Postal inspection request, 1965-1967 (Box 8)
    - Stories to work over, 1959- (Box 8)
    - "TELE-News Now" proposal, 1963 (Box 8)
    - "Voluntary 45 Dollars to USA" proposal, 1961 (Box 8)
    - "The White House Conference on International Cooperation", 1965 (Box 8)
    - Woman's Pavillion For HemisFair Exhibition, 1968 (Box 8)
    - World In Color Exhibition, 1968 (Box 8)
- Projects and assignments
  - Published books, The following four books were removed for cataloging 10/06
    - Bars on Her Shoulders, 1943; Written by Jean Stansbury, direction and photographs by Jackie Martin
    - Brazil Giant To the South, 1945; Written by Alice Rogers Hager, photos by Jackie Martin
    - Frontier By Air: Brazil Takes the Sky Road, 1942; Written by Alice Rogers Hager, photos by Jackie Martin
    - Washington: City of Destiny, 1949; Written by Alice Rogers Hager, photographs by Jackie Martin
  - WAAC book
    - Manuscript: Bars On Her Shoulders, 1942-1943 (Box 9)
  - Brazil books
    - Brazil travel receipts, 1941 (Box 9)
    - Clippings: Publicity of trip and book (Box 9)
    - Journals, hardcover (month dates only) (Box 9)
    - Memorabilia: Notes of trip, calling cards (Box 9)
    - Correspondence with magazines about Brazil: Giant to the South (Box 9)
    - Captions and notes for Giant to the South; pulled proofs and magazine coverage, 1942 (Box 9)
    - Manuscript, Giant to the South, forward and captions only (Box 9)
    - Manuscript and notes for "Surgical Miracle in Rio", 1941 (Box 9)
    - Photographs
      - Photographs for "Surgical Miracle in Rio" (Box 9)
      - Photographs and captions for "Mate Empire" appeared in Inter-American Monthly, 1942 (Box 9)
      - Photo proofs for Frontier By Air, 1942 (Box 9)
      - Originals for Brazil books (Box 9)
      - Brazil, 1941-1942; 5 folders (Box 9)
      - Contact prints from Brazil, some not Jackie Martin's (Box 9)
    - Background file: Clippings and pamphlets from Brazil, 3 folders; approximately 1500 photographs in this section (Box 9)
  - Washington: City of Destiny
    - Outline/partial manuscript (Box 10)
    - Photographs, originals for book, 1947-1949; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Blueprint of jacket for Washington... (Box 10)
    - Notes written for Washington... (Box 10)
    - Picture script and captions for Washington... (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 10)
    - Background files
      - Washington... (Box 10)
      - Press releases about Washington D.C. (Box 10)
      - Government Services Publications (Box 10)
      - Clippings about Washington D.C. (Box 10)
    - Publicity and book reviews, approximately 300 photographs in this section (Box 10)
  - Features, general, 1933-1949
    - "Additional caption material" (Box 10)
    - Reproduction record of photos and articles (Box 10)
    - "Denmark Brewery and Dairy", 1933 (Box 10)
    - "Drucie Snyder", 1949 (Box 10)
    - "Electron Microscope" (Box 10)
    - "Father Malof", Mar 1946-Apr 1946; not serviced (Box 10)
    - "Fort Benning, Ga", Nov 1949 (Box 10)
    - "Gourmets" (Box 10)
    - "Mattson Kidnap story", 1935-1936 (Box 10)
    - "Matthew Brady-Handy" story (Box 10)
    - "News Photography" typescript (Box 10)
    - "Olga Kahler story", 1941 (Box 10)
    - "President Truman at Cuban Embassy", 1947-1948 (Box 10)
    - "Margaret Chase Smith" (Box 10)
    - "Saudi Arabian Oil", 1948 (Box 10)
    - "Suicide story", 1934-1939 (Box 10)
    - "Women's Broadcast Convention", Jan 1948 (Box 10)
  - Published material: Magazine features
    Magazines are arranged alphabetically. After each titled folder are research files for individual feature assignments containing stories, photographs, captions, and notes. Research files are not available for all features.
    - American Weekly, 1947
      - "Eunice and Kennedy Tradition", 25 May 1947 (Box 10)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1945-1951
      - "Blair House", 03 Jul 1948 (Box 11)
        See also Projects and assignments: Published material: magazine features: Parade 1945-1950: "Blair House" 26 Jan 1947
      - "The Touch of Genius", 03 Jul 1951 (Box 11)
      - "Tribute in Stone", 21 Jan 1950 (Box 11)
    - Click, 1942 (Box 11)
    - Collier's, 1940-1948
      - "Mr. Ball Goes To Washington", 07 Dec 1940 (Box 11)
      - "Two-Party Gal", 12 Jun 1948; Mesta, McLean (Box 11)
    - Cosmopolitan, 1941-1945
      - "Modern Miracle Woman: Patricia Draint", Sep 1942 (Box 11)
      - "Modern Miracle Woman: Dr. Catherine MacFarlaine", Jun 1942 (Box 11)
      - "Modern Miracle Woman: Esther Richards", Apr 1941 (Box 11)
    - Country Gentleman, 1941-1944
      - Column typescripts (Box 11)
      - "A Bomb For Peacetime", Mar 1944 (Box 11)
      - "A Bomb For Peacetime" Aerosol Bombs, DDT, Apr 1944 (Box 11)
      - "Dogs of War", Apr 1944 (Box 11)
      - "Farmer's Favorites: Farm and Home Hour", Sep 1943 (Box 11)
      - "Lot's Goes On Here" Holtsville, Alabama, Mar 1941 (Box 11)
      - "Short Course To Satisfaction", Jun 1942 (Box 11)
      - "Women You Should Know: Mary Anderson", Nov 1943 (Box 11)
      - "Women You Should Know: Flo Hall - Women's Land Army", Aug 1943 (Box 11)
      - "Women You Should Know: Ruth Mitchel", Aug 1943; p.73 for Jackie Martin (Box 11)
      - "Women You Should Know: Anesia Machado", Sep 1943 (Box 11)
      - "Women You Should Know: Craig McGeachy", Oct 1943 (Box 11)
    - Em Guardia, 1943 (Box 11)
    - Family Circle, 1941-1943
      - "Capital Hostess", 29 Sep 1944 (Box 11)
    - Glamour, 1942-1944 (Box 11)
    - Inter-American Monthly, 1942-1944 (Box 11)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1941-1944
      - "How America Lives Questionaire", 1944 (Box 11)
      - "I Owe My Career To Losing a Leg", May 1944 (Box 11)
      - "A Hero Comes Home", Nov 1943 (Box 11)
      - "No Apples This Time", Jul 1944 (Box 11)
    - Leader Magazine, 1949 (Box 11)
    - LOOK, 1941-1945
      - "Army Nurses Overseas", 26 Jun 1945 (Box 12)
      - "683 College Girls Visit West", 03 Jun 1941; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Madamoiselle, 1945 (Box 12)
    - McCall's, 1943
      - "Ex-Servicemen Can Expect This", Oct 1943 (Box 12)
    - Mirror, 1943-1949
      - "Children's International Broadcast", 1947-1948 (Box 12)
      - "Glamour Pony of Youngest Set", 28 Sep 1947 (Box 12)
      - "Newest Art Medium", 12 Oct 1947 (Box 12)
      - "Star-Spangled Salon", 23 Nov 1943 (Box 12)
      - "Trophies of War" Luftwaif story (Box 12)
    - News-Week, 1937 (Box 12)
    - Parade, 1945-1950
      - "Air Route Speeds Wounded", 25 Mar 1945 (Box 12)
      - "Army Dietitian" (Box 12)
      - "Blair House", 26 Jan 1947 (Box 12)
        See also Projects and assignments: Published material: magazine features: Christian Science Monitor 1945-1951: "Blair House" 03 Jul 1948
      - "Handsomest Prince: Carl Gustav", 12 Mar 1950 (Box 12)
      - "U.S. Women in Foreign Service", 1949 (Box 12)
    - Pathfinder, 1946
      - "Vinson Swearing In", 17 Jul 1946 (Box 12)
    - Photo-News (Box 12)
    - Saturday Evening Post, 1931-1956
      - "Buyer No.1: Don Nelson", 14 Jun 1943 (Box 12)
      - "Curley Byrd Gets Worm", 28 Jun 1948 (Box 12)
      - "The House That Jesse Built", Mar 1942 (Box 12)
      - "Minor League Matthewson", 19 Jul 1941 (Box 12)
    - Skyways, 1942-1945
      - "Women As Service Pilots", Feb 1944; WASP (Box 12)
      - "Salon d'ecole air" (Box 12)
    - Stage, 1941 (Box 12)
    - This Week, 1941-1948
      - Mundt Story, 1948 (Box 12)
    - TIME
      - "Gromyko", 18 Aug 1947 (Box 12)
    - Town and Country, 1942-1945
      - Nurses Layout (Box 12)
      - "Red Cross Tent" (Box 12)
    - U.S. Camera, 1945
      - "Nurses Story", 1945 (Box 12)
    - Vogue, 1948-1949 (Box 12)
    - Who, 1941 (Box 12)
    - Woman's Home Companion, 1941-1943
      - "The Angelic Maples", May 1942 (Box 13)
      - "Let's Go Bowling!", Apr 1943 (Box 13)
      - "Mme Chiang Kai Shek", 24 Feb 1943 (Box 13)
      - "Trailer Town", Jul 1942 (Box 13)
      - "Will He Get My Letter?", May 1943 (Box 13)
  - Published material: Newspaper features
    - "Radio Idea" sample scripts, correspondence, 1928 (Box 13)
    - The Arcadia, 1927-1928 (Box 13)
    - "The Arcadians" scrapbook, 1927-1928 (Box 13)
    - Washington Daily News, 1929-1930; "Special Editions" edited by Jackie Martin; "Radio, Auto Show, Travel, etc" (Box 13)
    - Washington Daily News "Hoover Airport Plane Crash", 03 Nov 1931 (Box 13)
    - Washington Times-Herald: the first year, 1939-1940; related clippings and correspondence (Box 13)
    - Washington Times-Herald: last edition, 17 Mar 1954 (Box 13)
    - Washington Post: first edition; clippings related to the sale, 18 Mar 1954 (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheets; "Dixie's Dead End" by Cissy Patterson, photos by Jackie Martin, 1936-1937 (Box 13)
    - Clipping of George Gershwin, 1936; Reprinted in Washington Post (1957) (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheets; "Jackie in Movieland", 1937-1939; 50 Interviews from Hollywood; 6 folders (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheets; music and theater, 1939 (Box 13)
    - Captions and programs for music and theater (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheet; Jane Bartleman Interview, 22 Feb 1940 (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheets, 1938-1941; 1944-1950; 11 folders (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheet; "Eric: Hospital's Units Pride", 21 Jan 1945 (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheet; "Empty Boots", 24 Jan 1954 (Box 13)
    - Times-Herald tearsheet; "Red Cross Tent", 14 Mar 1945 (Box 13)
    - Chicago Sun tearsheets, 1941-1942 (Box 13)
    - New York World Telegram tearsheets, 1945 (Box 13)
    - New York Journal American tearsheet, "FBI Story", 1946 (Box 13)
    - Captions and programs; concerts, music, and theater, 1947-1948 (Box 13)
  - Newspaper features research files
    - "Fredericksburg Dog Mart," Times-Herald, 14 Oct 1939 (Box 13)
    - Laurel Race Track, Times-Herald, 05 Oct 1941 (Box 13)
    - Mrs. Palmer Hoyt, Times-Herald, 10 Nov 1945 (Box 13)
    - Tyson Barbeque, 1945 (Box 13)
    - Soviet Reception at Embassy: 25th Anniversary of Red Army and Navy, Times-Herald, 23 Feb 1946 (Box 13)
    - Holmes-Bassett wedding, Times-Herald, 28 Mar 1946 (Box 13)
    - Wife of General Clay Packs for Germany, Times-Herald, 04 Apr 1946 (Box 13)
    - Lady Astor at Dunbar High School, Times-Herald, 09 Apr 1946 (Box 13)
    - Callie Shaw - Social Mentor, Times-Herald, 09 Apr 1946 (Box 13)
    - Chinese Cardinal and Senator McCarran at Chinese Embassy, Times-Herald, 09 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Clare Boothe Luce (Predate), Times-Herald, Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Clare Boothe Luce's Birthday, Times-Herald, 10 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - White House Spanish Luncheon, Times-Herald, 19 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Noted Editors at Washington Convention, Times-Herald, 19 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - FBI (predate) J. E.Hoover with boyscouts, Times-Herald, 21 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Stanley Reed: new Chief Justice, Times-Herald, 22 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Archive (predate), Times-Herald, Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Mexican Embassy, Times-Herald, 23 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Korea's 1st Emissary Here: Miss Whang Koh, Times-Herald, 26 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Bendix VHF Radio, Times-Herald, 26 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Winifred Stillwell: General Bradley's aide, Times-Herald, 29 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Edith Nourse Rogers - Walter Reed Hospital, Times-Herald, 01 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Vinsons' Group Leave For Kentucky Derby, Times-Herald, 02 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Fertility Clinic, Times-Herald, 02 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Senator Brooks and Fiancee, Mrs. Peavey, Times-Herald, 04 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Matteo Mezzanotte and Claudia Stone Wed: Hollywood couple suicide, Times-Herald, 04 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Warrenton, Virginia Gold Cup Race, Times-Herald, 05 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - British Ambassador and Lady Halifax, Times-Herald, 14 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Navajo Indians at the Senate, Times-Herald, 14 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Sgt. John Hoffman Receives Soldier Medal, Times-Herald, 15 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - FBI: Flo Bratton, Deputy Sheriff, Times-Herald, 18 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Reception For General Roxas, Phillipines, Times-Herald, 18 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Mme. Loudon: Netherlandish Embassy, Times-Herald, 21 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Lille Dache at LeBaron Farm Cattle Show, Times-Herald, 21 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Mrs. Truman at Newspaper Women's Ball, Times-Herald, 24 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Spanish Class at Canadian Embassy, Times-Herald, 24 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - President Truman addresses Congress re: railroad strike, Times-Herald, 26 May 1946 (Box 14)
    - Naval Academy: June Week Festival, King, 05 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - New Chief Justice and Mrs. Vinson Sing, Times-Herald, 07 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - Hungarian Prime Minister, Ferenc Nagy, Times-Herald, 13 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - Officials Watching Louis Coun Fight, 19 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - Bernard Barach, Times-Herald, 28 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - Margaret Woodhouse Hired by Her Mother/Congresswoman, King, 26 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - National Women's Press Club Inauguration: Alice Rogers Hager receives award, 29 Jun 1946 (Box 14)
    - Helen Waterhouse Back From Yugoslavia, 10 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - Peace Monument, Capitol, Times-Herald, 12 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - Lion Statue and Capitol: Loan is Passed, New York Daily Journal, 13 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - The Ellipse-Nisei, Japanese-Americans Honored, Times-Herald, 15 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - Doctors Hospital - Premature Triplets, Times-Herald, 16 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - Officials' Wives Canning Food (Box 14)
    - Winifred Stillwell predate, Times-Herald, 21 Jul 1946; also 29 Apr 1946 (Box 14)
    - Rep. Helen Douglas Talks Atomic Energy, King, 27 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - May's Empty Chair: Amputees at Capitol Hill with Edith Nourse Rogers, King, 29 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - Senator Ball and Family, 31 Jul 1946 (Box 14)
    - Mrs. Tafts, 01 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Clare Boothe Luce and Amputees at Capitol, Times-Herald, 01 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Peter Mansfield and Children at Airport, at Home; Embassy, Times-Herald, 03 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Saudi Arabian Minister and American Wife, Times-Herald, 03 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Assistant Secretary of State William Benton and Czech Girl, Times-Herald, 04 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Red Cross Girl and 2 Dogs, 06 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - American Legion Youth Forum, Times-Herald, 08 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Boys' Forum Graduation, American University, 09 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - GI Veteran, Son at American University, Times-Herald, 10 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - Edith Debecker Sebald, 15 Aug 1946 (Box 14)
    - James Maloney, Acting Chief of Secret Service, 11 Sep 1946 (Box 14)
    - Evie Roberts portraits for E. Patterson, Times-Herald, 12 Sep 1946 (Box 14)
    - President Truman at Walter Reed Hospital, 13 Sep 1946 (Box 14)
    - General and Mamie Eisenhower, Times-Herald, 21 Sep 1946 (Box 14)
    - A. R. Hager, E. Johnston, W. Benton; UNESCO, 23 Sep 1946 (Box 14)
    - "Bristol Freighter" Wash. Airport; Mansfield, 23 Sep 1946 (Box 14)
    - John D. Hertz Receives Medal From Secretary of Arms, 12 Oct 1947 (Box 14)
    - Guillermo DeBelt, Ambassador of Cuba, Times-Herald, 02 Dec 1947 (Box 14)
    - Mme. Maria Martins, 1947 (Box 14)
    - Womens Press Club Party, 1947; Electroflash (Box 14)
    - Kenmore Association 25th Anniversary, 09 May 1947 (Box 14)
    - Francis Craig, Capitol Theater, 1947; "Near You" (Box 14)
    - Hoover Airport Plane Crash, 07 Nov 1947 (Box 14)
    - Eustis-Phillips Wedding, Times-Herald, 10 Oct 1949 (Box 14)
    - Greta Kempton Portraits, Times-Herald, 06 Feb 1949 (Box 14)
    - Job for David Berger (Box 14)
    - China Benefit Bazaar, Ann Archibald (Box 14)
  - War correspondent
    - Unpublished book on army nurses, working titles: "The Nurses: World War II," "The Army Nurses," "Nurses in Action," Medic!," "Oh Medick!" "War Nurse"
      - Manuscript, "The Nurses: World War II", original manuscript; first page has pencilled date of 1946 (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, "The Nurses: World War II", photocopy (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, "Army Nurses", photocopy (Box 15)
      - Manuscript: "Army Nurses: World War II", corrected carbon copy (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, The Nurses", early draft (Box 15)
      - "Medic: Murses in Action", partial typescript proposal (Box 15)
      - "The Nurses: World War II" statement of plan, 1960s (Box 15)
      - "The Nurses: World War II" correspondence, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Army Nurses: WW II typescripts, 1944 (Box 15)
      - Army Nurses: hospitals, typescripts, 1944 (Box 15)
      - Army Nurses: WW II background material (Box 15)
      - Army Nurses: WW II background material not used in final draft, 5 folders (Box 15)
      - Statistical material on nurses in service (Box 15)
      - "The Nurses: World War II" clippings and background (Box 15)
    - Army photo/story scrapbook (Box 16)
    - Captions for Signal Corps shots and Jackie Martin's, 1945 (Box 16)
    - Censored war stories, carbon typescripts (Box 16)
    - Clippings related to Jackie Martin's stories (Box 16)
    - Journal, notebooks, Jackie Martin's notes as war correspondent (Box 16)
    - Epinal, 1944; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - France, invasion, 1944 (Box 16)
    - Naples, Italy, 1944 (Box 16)
    - 93rd Evacuation Hospital, 1944 (Box 16)
    - Analysis of D-Day and southern invasion, 15 Aug 1944-10 Dec 1944 (Box 16)
    - Travel record, 1944-1945 (Box 16)
    - U.S. General Patch assignment for USIA (Box 16)
    - War correspondent background, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Women in diplomatic service, 1947 (Box 16)
    - War notes, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - War decoration ceremony, Jackie Martin receives award (Box 16)
  - American Battle Monuments Commission (ABMC), 1967
    - Travel records on ABMC assignment (Box 16)
    - Correspondence
      - Memos from inside the ABMC (Box 16)
      - Memos from Jackie Martin inside the ABMC (Box 16)
      - ABMC requests for information re: human interest stories (Box 16)
      - ABMC requests for information to Jackie Martin (Box 16)
      - Requests for information re: impressions of ABMC from visitors to cemeteries and memorials (Box 16)
    - Transcripts
      - ABMC dedication speeches, 1956 (Box 16)
      - "Far and Above Our Poor Power" and "Memorial Day" by George Kent (Box 16)
    - Notes on ABMC (Box 16)
    - Clippings: Quotes saved by Jackie Martin for General Dever's proposal (Box 16)
    - Background files
      - About ABMC (Box 16)
      - Booklets and articles about ABMC (Box 16)
      - Booklets of American memorials and cemeteries on foreign land (Box 17)
      - Notes and correspondence (Box 17)
    - Subject file: Pan-Am Brussels (Box 17)
    - Photographs
      - War maps (Box 17)
      - American memorials and cemeteries (Box 17)
      - Contact prints of cemeteries and memorials (Box 17)
      - Color photos for ABMC of memorials (Box 17)
      - ABMC photos labeled on back (Box 17)
      - Netherlands War Graves Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 17)
      - Originally an ABMC photo scrapbook (Box 17)
      - ABMC (Normandy), approximately 400 photographs in this section; See Photographs: Various feature and news photos (Oversize 1)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA), Federal Services, 1950-1957
    - USIA Marshall Plan: "Hungarian Appeal 1952: Analysis and Coding Manual for Still Photography", See Photographs: Marshall Plan... (Oversize 1)
    - "Family of Man" exhibition
      - Photo album: Exhibition at Corcoran Gallery, Washington D.C., 1955 (Box 17)
      - Photo album: Exhibition in various cities (Box 17)
      - Research file, 1955-1957 (Box 17)
      - Family of Man, (exhibition catalog) 2 copies, 1 which is marked (Box 17)
      - Typescripts: speeches by Edward Steichen, 1955 (Box 17)
    - Fact sheets: USIA Europe Photo Branch, 1950-1955 (Box 17)
    - Photographs: USIA Paris Photo Conference, 1952 (Box 17)
    - Denmark photo/story assignment (Box 17)
    - Typescripts
      - USIA Paris Photo Conference speeches, 1952 (Box 17)
      - USIA "Marshall Plan and We" filmstrip no. 1 (Box 17)
      - USIA "Marshall Plan and We" filmstrips no.11 through no.33 and no.914.5 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence
      - "Family of Man" with Edward Steichen, 1950-1955 (Box 18)
      - USIA incoming to Jackie Martin, 1950-1955 (Box 18)
      - USIA outgoing from Jackie Martin, 1950-1955 (Box 18)
      - Re: Marshall Plan Project (Box 18)
    - Background file: USIA Marshall Plan Foundation/Library, plan for documentation of Information Operation (Box 18)
    - Recommendations and Ratings: USIA evaluation of Jackie Martin (Box 18)
    - Travel orders and medical records, 1950-1954 (Box 18)